<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="VivekanandVision">

        <item>“Take risks in your life, If you win, you can lead! If you loose, you can guide!"</item>
        <item> “Strength is life; weakness is death.”</item>
        <item>“Experience is the only teacher we have. we may talk and reason all our lives,
            but we shall not understand a word of truth.”</item>
        <item> “If you think yourselves strong, strong you will be.”</item>
        <item>“Take up one idea, make that one idea your life. Think of it, dream of it,
            Live on that idea let the brain, muscles, nerves, every part of your body be full of that idea,
            and just leave every other idea alone. This is the way to success.”  </item>
        <item>Serve man Serve God.</item>
        <item>They alone live, who live for others.</item>
        <item>Neither seek nor avoid, take what comes.</item>
        <item>You are the creator of your own destiny.</item>
        <item>In one word, this ideal is that you are divine.</item>
        <item>The greatest sin is to think that you are weak.</item>
        <item> External nature is only internal nature writ large.</item>
        <item>Arise, awake and stop not till the goal is reached.</item>
        <item>Never think there is anything impossible for the soul.</item>
        <item>You cannot believe in God until you believe in yourself.</item>
        <item>All power is within you; you can do anything and everything.</item>
        <item>In a conflict between the heart and the brain, follow your heart.</item>
        <item>Desire, ignorance, and inequality—this is the trinity of bondage.</item>
        <item>Blessed are they whose bodies get destroyed in the service of others.</item>
        <item>That man has reached immortality who is disturbed by nothing material.</item>
        <item>The world is the great gymnasium where we come to make ourselves strong.</item>
        <item>Truth can be stated in a thousand different ways, yet each one can be true.</item>
        <item> The fire that warms us can also consume us; it is not the fault of the fire.</item>
        <item>Meditation can turn fools into sages but unfortunately, fools never meditate.</item>
        <item>Both attachment and detachment perfectly developed make a man great and happy.</item>
        <item>The power of concentration is the only key to the treasure-house of knowledge.</item>
        <item>The greatest religion is to be true to your own nature. Have faith in yourselves.</item>
        <item>You will be nearer to heaven through football than through the study of the Gita.</item>
        <item>GOD is to be worshipped as the one beloved, dearer than everything in this and next life.</item>
        <item>“Stand up, be bold, and take the blame on your own shoulders. Do not go about throwing mud at other;
            for all the faults you suffer from, you are the sole and only cause.”</item>
        <item>“Learn everything that is good from others, but bring it in, and in your own way adsorb it;
            do not become others.”</item>
        <item>“You should work like a master and not as a slave; work incessantly, but do not do a slave’s work.”</item>
        <item> “Whatever you believe, that you will be, If you believe yourselves to be ages, ages you will be tomorrow.
            There is nothing to obstruct you.”</item>
        <item>“If i love myself despite my infinite faults, how can i hate anyone at the glimpse of a few faults”..!</item>
        <item>“All power is within you. You can do anything and everything. Believe in that. Do not believe that you are weak;
            do ot believe that you are half-crazy lunatics, as most of us do nowadays. Stand up and express the divinity within
            you.”</item>
        <item>That which is selfish is immoral, and that which is unselfish is moral.</item>
        <item>“Talk to yourself once in a day.. otherwise you may miss meeting an excellent person in this world.”</item>
        <item> “Throw away all weakness. tell your body that it is strong. Tell your mind that it is
            strong and have unbound faith and hope in yourself.”</item>
        <item> “When you are doing any work.. do it as worship, as he highest worship,
            and devote your whole life to it for the time being.”</item>
        <item>“The mistake is that we want to tie the whole world down
            to our own plane of thought and to make out mind the measure of the whole universe.”</item>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="VivekanandTitle">
        <item>Introduction </item>
        <item>National Youth Day </item>
        <item>Vivekanand in Family </item>
        <item>How did he in study and activities? </item>
        <item>Vivekanand asked does god exist? </item>
        <item>What answer Vivekanand get? </item>
        <item>Vivekanand asked god to give some? </item>
        <item>RamKrishna Death</item>
        <item>Taking shape of Vivekanand</item>
        <item>Decision to cure the diseases of society.</item>
        <item>World introduction to Vivekanand</item>
        <item>Swami Ji work and Methodology to Success</item>
        <item>Fixed appointment with God</item>
        <item>Netaji Subhash Chandra Bose surrender to Swami Ji</item>
        <item>One Memory </item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="VivekanandLife">
        <item>Brief Summary About Vivekanand </item>
        <item>Why 12 January ? </item>
        <item>One of Eight son of his Mother </item>
        <item>What do you think ? </item>
        <item>Does he found answer ? </item>
        <item>Guess Yes or NO... </item>
        <item>God give me some to become great. </item>
        <item>Loss of Guru a bad NEWS </item>
        <item>Now the time has come..</item>
        <item>A great decision has been finalised.</item>
        <item>How he achieved name and fame beginning...</item>
        <item>"Arise Awake and Stop not till the Goal is Reached"</item>
        <item>Mahasamadhi and says good bye to World</item>
        <item>Swami Vivekanand spirit of India </item>
        <item> Does Mahatma Gandhi ever meet Swami Ji?</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="VivekanandStory">

        <item>
            Date of Birth: January12, 1863"\n\n"

            Place of Birth: Calcutta, Bengal Presidency (Now Kolkata in West Bengal)"\n\n"

            Parents: Vishwanath Dutta (Father) and Bhuvaneshwari Devi (Mother)"\n\n"

            Education: Calcutta Metropolitan School; Presidency College, Calcutta"\n\n"

            Institutions: Ramakrishna Math; Ramakrishna Mission; Vedanta Society of New York"\n\n"

            Religious Views: Hinduism"\n\n"

            Philosophy: Advaita Vedanta"\n\n"

            Publications: Karma Yoga (1896); Raja Yoga (1896); Lectures from Colombo to Almora (1897); My Master (1901)"\n\n"

            Death: July 4, 1902"\n\n"

            Place of Death: Belur Math, Belur, Bengal"\n\n"

            Memorial: Belur Math, Belur, West Bengal"\n\n"
        </item>

        <item>Swami Vivekananda was a Hindu monk and one of the most celebrated spiritual leaders of India.
            He was more than just a spiritual mind, he was a prolific thinker, great orator and passionate patriot.
            He carried on the free-thinking philosophy of his guru, Ramakrishna Paramhansa forward into a new paradigm."\n"
            He worked tirelessly towards betterment of the society, in servitude of the poor and needy,
            dedicating his all for his country. He was responsible for the revival of Hindu spiritualism and established
            Hinduism as a revered religion on world stage. His message of universal brotherhood and self-awakening remains
            relevant especially in the current backdrop of widespread political turmoil around the world. The young monk and
            his teachings have been an inspiration to many, and his words have become goals of self-improvement especially for
            the youth of the country. For this very reason, his birthday January 12, is celebrated as the
            National Youth Day in India.</item>

        <item>Born Narendranath Dutta, into an affluent Bengali family in Calcutta, Vivekananda was one
            of the eight children of Vishwanath Dutta and Bhuvaneshwari Devi. He was born on January 12,
            1863, on the occasion of Makar Sankranti. Father Vishwanath was a successful attorney with considerable
            influence in society. Narendranath’s mother Bhuvaneshwari was a woman endowed with a strong, God-fearing
            mind who had a great impact on her son. </item>

        <item>As a young boy, Narendranath displayed sharp intellect. His mischievous nature belied his interest in music,
            both instrumental as well as vocal. He excelled in his studies as well, first at the Metropolitan institution,
            and later at the Presidency College in Calcutta. By the time he graduated from the college, he had acquired a
            vast knowledge of different subjects. He was active in sports, gymnastics, wrestling and body building. He was
            an avid reader and read up on almost everything under the sun. He perused the Hindu scriptures like the Bhagvad
            Gita and the Upanishads on one hand, while on the other hand he studied western philosophy, history and spirituality
            by David Hume, Johann Gottlieb Fichte and Herbert Spencer.</item>

        <item>Although Narendranath’s mother was a devout woman and he had grown up in a religious atmosphere
            at home, he underwent a deep spiritual crisis at the start of his youth. His well-studied knowledge
            led him to question the existence of God and for some time he believed in Agnosticism. Yet he could
            not completely ignore the existence of a Supreme Being. He became associated with Brahmo Movement led
            by Keshab Chandra Sen, for some time. The Bramho Samaj recognised one God unlike the idol-worshipping,
            superstition-ridden Hinduism. The host of philosophical questions regarding the existence of God roiling
            through his mind remained unanswered. During this spiritual crisis, Vivekananda first heard about
            Sri Ramakrishna from William Hastie, the Principal of the Scottish Church College.</item>

        <item>Earlier, to satisfy his intellectual quest for God, Narendranath visited prominent spiritual
            leaders from all religions, asking them a single question, “Have you seen God?” Each time he came
            away without a satisfying answer."\n"
            He put forward the same question to Sri Ramkrishna at his residence in Dakshinewar Kali Temple compounds.
            Without a moment\'s hesitation, Sri Ramakrishna replied: "Yes, I have. I see God as clearly as I see you,
            only in a much deeper sense". Vivekananda, initially unimpressed by the simplicity of Ramkrishna, was
            astonished with Ramakrishna\'s reply. Ramakrishna gradually won over this argumentative young man with his
            patience and love. The more Narendranath visited Dakshineshwar, the more his questions were answered.</item>

        <item>In 1884, Naredranath underwent a considerable financial distress due to the death of his
            father as he had to support his mother and younger siblings. He asked Ramakrishna to pray to
            the Goddess for the financial welfare of his family. On Ramakrishna’s suggestion he himself
            went to the temple to pray. But once he faced the Goddess he could not ask for money and wealth,
            instead he asked for ‘Vivek’ (conscience) and ‘Bairagya’ (reclusion). That day marked the complete
            spiritual awakening of Narendranath and he found himself drawn to an ascetic way of life.</item>

        <item>During the middle of 1885, Ramakrishna, who had been suffering from throat cancer, fell seriously ill.
            In September 1885, Sri Ramakrishna was moved to Shyampukur in Culcutta, and a few months later Narendranath
            took a rented villa at Cossipore. Here, he formed a group of young people who were ardent followers of
            Sri Ramakrishna and together they nursed their Guru with devoted care. On 16 August 1886, Sri Ramakrishna
            gave up his mortal body.</item>

        <item>After the demise of Sri Ramakrishna, around fifteen of his disciples including Narendranath
            began to live together in a dilapidated building at Baranagar in North Calcutta, which was
            named Ramakrishna Math, the monastic order of Ramakrishna. Here, in 1887, they formally renounced
            all ties to the world and took vows of monkhood. The brotherhood rechristened themselves and
            Narendranath emerged as Vivekananda meaning "the bliss of discerning wisdom". </item>

        <item>The brotherhood lived off on alms donated voluntarily by patrons during holy begging or ‘madhukari’,
            performed yoga and meditation. Vivekananda left the Math in 1886 and went on a tour of India on foot
            as a ‘Parivrajak’. He travelled the breadth of the country, absorbing much of the social, cultural and
            religious aspects of the people he came in contact with. He witnessed the adversities of life that the
            common people faced, their ailments, and vowed to dedicate his life to bring relief to these suffering.</item>

        <item>During the course of his wanderings, he came to know about the World Parliament of Religions
            being held in Chicago, America in 1893. He was keen to attend the meeting, to represent India,
            Hinduism and his Guru Sri Ramakrishna’s philosophies. He found assertion of his wishes while he was
            meditating on the rocks of Kanyakumari, the southernmost tip of India. Money was raised by his disciples
            in Madras (now Chennai) and Ajit Singh, Raja of Khetri, and Vivekananda left for Chicago on May 31, 1893 from Bombay.
            "\n\n"
            He faced insurmountable hardships on his way to Chicago, but his spirits remained as indomitable as ever.
            On 11 September 1893, when the time came, he took the stage and stunned everyone with his opening line
            “My brothers and sisters of America”. He received a standing ovation from the audience for the opening phrase.
            He went on to describe the principles of Vedanta and their spiritual significance, putting Hinduism on the map of
            World Religions.He spent the next two and a half years in America and founded the Vedanta Society of New York in
            1894. He also travelled to the United Kingdom to preach the tenets of the Vedanta and Hindu Spiritualism
            to the western world.</item>

        <item>Vivekananda returned to India in 1897 amidst warm reception from the common and royal alike.
            He reached Calcutta after a series of lectures across the country and founded the Ramakrishna Mission
            on May 1, 1897 at Belur Math near Calcutta. The goals of the Ramakrishna Mission were based on the ideals
            of Karma Yoga and its primary objective was to serve the poor and distressed population of the country.
            The Ramakrishna Mission undertook various forms of social service like establishing and running school,
            collages and hospitals, propagation of practical tenets of Vedanta through conference, seminars and workshops,
            initiating relief and rehabilitation work across the country.
            "\n\n"
            His religious conscience was an amalgamation of Sri Ramakrishna’s spiritual teachings of Divine manifestation
            and his personal internalization of the Advaita Vedanta philosophy. He directed to achieve the divinity of the
            soul by undertaking selfless work, worship and mental discipline. According to Vivekananda, the ultimate goal is
            to achieve freedom of the soul and that encompasses the entirety of one’s religion. "\n\n"

            Swami Vivekananda was a prominent nationalist, and had the overall welfare of his countrymen topmost
            in his mind. He urged his fellow countrymen to “Arise, awake and stop not till the goal is reached”.</item>

        <item>
            Swami Vivekananda had predicted that he will not live till the age of forty. On July 4, 1902,
            he went about his days’ work at the Belur Math, teaching Sanskrit grammar to the pupils.
            He retired to his room in the evening and died during meditation at around 9. He is said to have attained
            ‘Mahasamadhi’ and the great saint was cremated on the Banks of river Ganga.
        </item>

        <item>
            Swami Vivekananda revealed to the world the true foundations of India\'s unity as a nation.
            He taught how a nation with such a vast diversity can be bound together by a feeling of humanity
            and brother-hood. "\n\n"

            Vivekananda emphasized the points of drawbacks of western culture and the contribution of India to overcome
            those. Netaji Subhash Chandra Bose once said: "Swamiji harmonized the East and the West, religion and science,
            past and present. And that is why he is great. Our countrymen have gained unprecedented self-respect, self-reliance
            and self-assertion from his teachings." "\n\n"

            Vivekananda was successful in constructing a virtual bridge between the culture of East and the West. He
            interpreted the Hindu scriptures, philosophy and the way of life to the Western people. He made them realize
            that in spite of poverty and backwardness, India had a great contribution to make to world culture.
            He played a key role in ending India\'s cultural isolation from the rest of the world.
        </item>

    <item>Mahatma Gandhi once visited West Bengal in matter of some work, he does not get any living arrangement,
        and was roaming in Calcutta, so he decided to have a Glimpse of Swami Vivekanand, but when he reached Math, he come
        to know that Swami ji was ill (suffering from fever), and he was not present in Math, so Mahatma Gandhi missed
        to meet Swami Vivekanand The Spirit of India.</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="GandhiVision">
        <item>“Live as if you were to die tomorrow. Learn as if you were to live forever.”</item>
        <item>“A man is but a product of his thoughts. What he thinks he becomes.”</item>
        <item> “Be the change that you want to see in the world.”</item>
        <item> “The weak can never forgive. Forgiveness is an attribute of the strong.”</item>
        <item>“I will not let anyone walk through my mind with their dirty feet.”</item>
        <item>“Strength does not come from physical capacity. It comes from an indomitable will.”</item>
        <item>“An ounce of patience is worth more than a tonne of preaching.”</item>
        <item>“Change yourself – you are in control.”</item>
        <item>“See the good in people and help them.”</item>
        <item>“Without action, you aren’t going anywhere.”</item>
        <item>“Take care of this moment.”</item>
        <item>“Be congruent, be authentic, be your true self.”</item>
        <item>“Continue to grow and evolve.”</item>
        <item>“A no uttered from the deepest conviction is better than a ‘Yes’
            uttered merely to please, or worse, to avoid trouble.”</item>
        <item>“Glory lies in the attempt to reach one’s goal and not in reaching it.”</item>
        <item>"An eye for an eye will make the whole world blind.”</item>
        <item>“Happiness is when what you think, what you say, and what you do are in harmony.”</item>
        <item>“A coward is incapable of exhibiting love; it is the prerogative of the brave.”</item>
        <item>“Nobody can hurt me without my permission.”</item>
        <item>“In a gentle way, you can shake the world.”</item>
    </string-array>

<string-array name="GandhiTitle">
    <item>Introduction</item>
    <item>International Day of Non-Voilence</item>
    <item>Glipse of Childhood</item>
    <item>As a Teenager </item>
    <item>Education </item>
    <item>In Foreign</item>
    <item>Reason Behind Congress Party</item>
    <item>Mistry of Champaran</item>
    <item>A new movement was taking shape</item>
    <item>Khilafat Movement</item>
    <item>Non-cooperation Movement </item>
    <item>Swaraj</item>
    <item>Simmion Commision</item>
    <item>Buiseness over Table</item>
    <item>Final War with British Government</item>
    <item>When A Country broke down</item>
    <item>Death or End </item>
    <item>Why portrait as National Father of India?</item>
    <item>Mahatma</item>

</string-array>
    <string-array name="GandhiLife">
        <item>Background Details</item>
        <item>Why 2nd October ?</item>
        <item>How it was?</item>
        <item>Addicted with ..</item>
        <item>Was he good at school?</item>
        <item>What happened in South Africa</item>
        <item>How it comes into People\'s life</item>
        <item>Champaran Satyagrah</item>
        <item>Kheda Satyagrah</item>
        <item>Could not happen ?</item>
        <item>Gandhi vow..</item>
        <item>Foundation has been inaugurated..</item>
        <item>Salt Satyagrah and Dandi March</item>
        <item>Round Table Conference</item>
        <item>Quit India Movement</item>
        <item>Two parts of One Country</item>
        <item>Sad News or Good News ?</item>
        <item>Reason behind Legend</item>
        <item>Foriegners does not know?</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="GandhiStory">
        <item>Date of Birth: October 2, 1869"\n\n"
            Place of Birth: Porbandar, British India (now Gujarat)"\n\n"
            Date of Death: January 30, 1948"\n\n"
            Place of Death: Delhi, India"\n\n"
            Cause of Death: Assassination"\n\n"
            Professions: Lawyer, politician, activist, writer"\n\n"
            Spouse: Kasturba Gandhi"\n\n"
            Children: Harilal Gandhi, Manilal Gandhi, Ramdas Gandhi and Devdas Gandhi"\n\n"
            Father: Karamchand Uttamchand Gandhi"\n\n"
            Mother: Putlibai Gandhi"\n\n"</item>

        <item>Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi was an eminent freedom activist and an influential political
            leader who played a dominant role in India\'s struggle for independence. Gandhi is known
            by different names, such as Mahatma (a great soul), Bapuji (endearment for father in Gujarati)
            and Father of the Nation. Every year, his birthday is celebrated as Gandhi Jayanti, a national
            holiday in India, and also observed as the International Day of Nonviolence. Mahatma Gandhi,
            as he is most commonly referred to, was instrumental in liberating India from the clutches of
            the British. With his unusual yet powerful political tools of Satyagraha and non-violence,
            he inspired several other political leaders all over the world including the likes of
            Nelson Mandela, Martin Luther King Jr and Aung San Suu Kyi. Gandhi, apart from helping India
            triumph in its fight for independence against the English, also led a simple and righteous life,
            for which he is often revered. Gandhi\'s early life was pretty much ordinary, and he became a great
            man during the course of his life. This is one of the main reasons why Gandhi is followed by millions,
            for he proved that one can become a great soul during the course of one\’s life, should they possess the
            will to do so</item>

        <item>M. K. Gandhi was born in the princely state of Porbandar, which is located in modern-day Gujarat.
            He was born into a Hindu merchant caste family to Karamchand Gandhi, diwan of Porbandar and his fourth
            wife, Putlibai. Gandhi\’s mother belonged to an affluent Pranami Vaishnava family. As a child, Gandhi was
            a very naughty and mischievous kid. In fact, his sister Raliat had once revealed that hurting dogs by
            twisting their ears was among Maohandas favorite pastime. During the course of his childhood, Gandhi
            befriended Sheikh Mehtab, who was introduced to him by his older brother. Gandhi, who was raised by a
            vegetarian family, started eating meat. It is also said that a young Gandhi accompanied Sheikh to a brothel,
            but left the place after finding it uncomfortable. Gandhi, along with one of his relatives, also cultivated
            the habit of smoking after watching his uncle smoke. After smoking the leftover cigarettes, thrown away by
            his uncle, Gandhi started stealing copper coins from his servants in order to buy Indian cigarettes. When he
            could no longer steal, he even decided to commit suicide such was Gandhi\’s addiction to cigarettes. At the age
            of fifteen, after stealing a bit of gold from his friend Sheikh\’s armlet, Gandhi felt remorseful and confessed
            to his father about his stealing habit and vowed to him that he would never commit such mistakes again.</item>

        <item>In his early years, Gandhi was deeply influenced by the stories of Shravana and Harishchandra that reflected
            the importance of truth. Through these stories and from his personal experiences, he realized that truth and
            love are among the supreme values. Mohandas married Kasturba Makhanji at the age of 13. Gandhi later went on
            to reveal that the marriage didn\’t mean anything to him at that age and that he was happy and excited only about
            wearing new set of clothes. But then as days passed by, his feelings for her turned lustful, which he later confessed
            with regret in his autobiography. Gandhi had also confessed that he could no more concentrate in school because
            of his mind wavering towards his new and young wife.</item>

        <item>After his family moved to Rajkot, a nine year old Gandhi was enrolled at a local school, where he studied
            the basics of arithmetic, history, geography and languages. When he was 11 years old, he attended a high school
            in Rajkot. He lost an academic year in between because of his wedding but later rejoined the school and eventually
            completed his schooling. He then dropped out of Samaldas College in Bhavnagar State after joining it in the year 1888.
            Later Gandhi was advised by a family friend Mavji Dave Joshiji to pursue law in London. Excited by the idea,
            Gandhi managed to convince his mother and wife by vowing before them that he would abstain from eating meat
            and from having sex in London. Supported by his brother, Gandhi left to London and attended the Inner Temple
            and practiced law. During his stay in London, Gandhi joined a Vegetarian Society and was soon introduced to
            Bhagavad Gita by some of his vegetarian friends. The contents of Bhagavad Gita would later have a massive
            influence on his life. He came back to India after being called to the bar by Inner Temple.</item>

        <item>After returning to India, Gandhi struggled to find work as a lawyer. In 1893, Dada Abdullah,
            a merchant who owned a shipping business in South Africa asked if he would be interested to serve
            as his cousin\’s lawyer in South Africa. Gandhi gladly accepted the offer and left to South Africa,
            which would serve as a turning point in his political career. "\n\n"
            In South Africa, he faced racial discrimination directed towards blacks and Indians. He faced humiliation
            on many occasions but made up his mind to fight for his rights. This turned him into an activist and he
            took upon him many cases that would benefit the Indians and other minorities living in South Africa.
            Indians were not allowed to vote or walk on footpaths as those privileges were limited strictly to the
            Europeans. Gandhi questioned this unfair treatment and eventually managed to establish an organization
            named ‘Natal Indian Congress\’ in 1894. After he came across an ancient Indian literature known as ‘Tirukkural’,
            which was originally written in Tamil and later translated into many languages, Gandhi was influenced by the
            idea of Satyagraha (devotion to the truth) and implemented non-violent protests around 1906. After spending
            21 years in South Africa, where he fought for civil rights, he had transformed into a new person and he returned
            to India in 1915</item>

        <item>After his long stay in South Africa and his activism against the racist policy of the British,
            Gandhi had earned the reputation as a nationalist, theorist and organiser. Gopal Krishna Gokhale,
            a senior leader of the Indian National Congress, invited Gandhi to join India\’s struggle for independence
            against the British Rule. Gokhale thoroughly guided Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi about the prevailing political
            situation in India and also the social issues of the time. He then joined the Indian National
            Congress and before taking over the leadership in 1920, headed many agitations which he named Satyagraha.</item>

        <item>The Champaran agitation in 1917 was the first major success of Gandhi after his arrival in India.
            The peasants of the area were forced by the British landlords to grow Indigo, which was a cash crop,
            but its demand had been declining. To make the matters worse, they were forced to sell their crops to
            the planters at a fixed price. The farmers turned to Gandhiji for help. Pursuing a strategy of nonviolent
            agitation, Gandhi took the administration by surprise and was successful in getting concessions from the
            authorities. This campaign marked Gandhi\’s arrival in India!</item>

        <item>Farmers asked the British to relax the payment of taxes as Kheda was hit by floods in 1918.
            When the British failed to pay heed to the requests, Gandhi took the case of the farmers and led
            the protests. He instructed them to refrain from paying revenues no matter what. Later, the British
            gave in and accepted to relax the revenue collection and gave its word to Vallabhbhai Patel, who had
            represented the farmers.</item>

        <item>Gandhi had agreed to support the British during their fight in World War I.
            But the British failed to grant independence post the war, as promised earlier,
            and as a result of this Khilafat Movement was launched. Gandhi realized that Hindus
            and Muslims must unite to fight the British and urged both the communities to show
            solidarity and unity. But his move was questioned by many Hindu leaders. Despite the
            opposition from many leaders, Gandhi managed to amass the support of Muslims. But as
            the Khilafat Movement ended abruptly, all his efforts evaporated into thin air.</item>

        <item>Non-cooperation Movement was one of Gandhi\’s most important movements against the British.
            Gandhi\’s urged his fellow countrymen to stop co-operation with the British. He believed that
            the British succeeded in India only because of the co-operation of the Indians. He had cautioned
            the British not to pass the Rowlatt Act, but they did not pay any attention to his words and passed
            the Act. As announced, Gandhiji asked everyone to start civil disobedience against the British.
            The British began suppressing the civil disobedience movement by force and opened fire on a peaceful
            crowd in Delhi. The British asked Gandhiji to not enter Delhi which he defied as a result of which he
            was arrested and this further enraged people and they rioted. He urged people to show unity, non-violence
            and respect for human life. But the British responded aggressively to this and arrested many protesters. "\n\n"
            On 13 April 1919, a British officer, Dyer, ordered his forces to open fire on a peaceful gathering,
            including women and children, in Amritsar\’s Jallianwala Bagh. As a result of this, hundreds of
            innocent Hindu and Sikh civilians were killed. The incident is known as ‘Jallianwala Bagh Massacre\’.
            But Gandhi criticized the protesters instead of blaming the English and asked Indians to use love
            while dealing with the hatred of British. He urged the Indians to refrain from all kinds of non-violence
            and went on fast-to-death to pressure Indians to stop their rioting.</item>

        <item>The concept of non-cooperation became very popular and started spreading through the
            length and breadth of India. Gandhi extended this movement and focused on Swaraj.
            He urged people to stop using British goods. He also asked people to resign from government
            employment, quit studying in British institutions and stop practicing in law courts.
            However, the violent clash in Chauri Chaura town of Uttar Pradesh, in February 1922, forced
            Gandhiji to call-off the movement all of a sudden. Gandhi was arrested on 10th March 1922 and
            was tried for sedition. He was sentenced to six years imprisonment, but served only two years in prison.</item>

        <item>During the period of 1920s, Mahatma Gandhi concentrated on resolving the wedge between the Swaraj
            Party and the Indian National Congress. In 1927, British had appointed Sir John Simon as the head of
            a new constitutional reform commission, popularly known as ‘Simon Commission’. There was not even a single
            Indian in the commission. Agitated by this, Gandhi passed a resolution at the Calcutta Congress in December 1928,
            calling on the British government to grant India dominion status. In case of non-compliance with this demand, the
            British were to face a new campaign of non-violence, having its goal as complete independence for the country. The
            resolution was rejected by the British. The flag of India was unfurled by the Indian national Congress
            on 31st December 1929 at its Lahore session. January 26, 1930 was celebrated as the Independence Day of India."\n\n"
            But the British failed to recognize it and soon they levied a tax on salt and Salt Satyagraha was launched
            in March 1930, as an opposition to this move. Gandhi started the Dandi March with his followers in March,
            going from Ahmedabad to Dandi on foot. The protest was successful and resulted in the Gandhi-Irwin Pact
            in March 1931.</item>

        <item>Post the Gandhi-Irwin Pact, Gandhi was invited to round table conferences by the British.
            While Gandhi pressed for the Indian independence, British questioned Gandhi\’s motives and asked
            him not to speak for the entire nation. They invited many religious leaders and B. R. Ambedkar
            to represent the untouchables. The British promised many rights to various religious groups as well
            as the untouchables. Fearing this move would divide India further, Gandhi protested against this by fasting.
            After learning about the true intentions of the British during the second conference, he came up with another
            Satyagraha, for which he was once again arrested.</item>

        <item>As the World War II progressed, Mahatma Gandhi intensified his protests for the complete
            independence of India. He drafted a resolution calling for the British to Quit India.
            The \'Quit India Movement\' or the \'Bharat Chhodo Andolan\' was the most aggressive movement
            launched by the Indian national Congrees under the leadership of Mahatma Gandhi.
            Gandhi was arrested on 9th August 1942 and was held for two years in the Aga Khan Palace in Pune,
            where he lost his secretary, Mahadev Desai and his wife, Kasturba. The Quit India Movement came to
            an end by the end of 1943, when the British gave hints that complete power would be transferred
            to the people of India. Gandhi called off the movement which resulted in the release
            of 100,000 political prisoners.</item>

        <item>The independence cum partition proposal offered by the British Cabinet Mission in 1946 was accepted
            by the Congress, despite being advised otherwise by Mahatma Gandhi. Sardar Patel convinced Gandhi that
            it was the only way to avoid civil war and he reluctantly gave his consent. After India\'s independence,
            Gandhi focused on peace and unity of Hindus and Muslims. He launched his last fast-unto-death in Delhi,
            and asked people to stop communal violence and emphasized that the payment of Rs. 55 crores, as per the
            Partition Council agreement, be made to Pakistan. Ultimately, all political leaders conceded to his wishes
            and he broke his fast.</item>

        <item>The inspiring life of Mahatma Gandhi came to an end on 30th January 1948, when he was shot by a fanatic,
            Nathuram Godse, at point-blank range. Nathuram was a Hindu radical, who held Gandhi responsible for
            weakening India by ensuring the partition payment to Pakistan. Godse and his co-conspirator,
            Narayan Apte, were later tried and convicted. They were executed on 15th November 1949. </item>

        <item>Mahatma Gandhi proposed the acceptance and practice of truth, non-violence, vegetarianism,
            Brahmacharya (celibacy), simplicity and faith in God. Though he would be remembered forever as
            the man who fought for Indian independence, his greatest legacies are the tools he used in his fight
            against the British. These methods inspired several other world leaders in their struggle against injustice.
            His statues are installed all over the world and he is considered the most prominent
            personality in Indian history.</item>

        <item>The word Mahatma is often mistaken in the West as Gandhi\’s first name.
            His extraordinary life inspired innumerable works of art in the field of literature,
            art and showbiz. Many movies and documentaries have been made on the life of the Mahatma.
            Post the Independence, Gandhi\’s image became the mainstay of Indian paper currency.</item>

    </string-array>

</resources>